let quiz = {
    chapter: 'Reproductive Health',
    topics: [
        'Repro Health Problem & Strategies',
        'Population Explosion',
        'Birth Control',
        'MTP',
        'STD',
        'Infertility',
    ],
    title: 'Reproductive Health Ex1',
    colors: ['#096c86', '#096c8636', '#dbf6fb'],
    questions: [
        {
            question: 'GIFT is',
            options: [
                'Embryo implantation after in vivo fertilization',
                'Sperm injection for in vivo fertilization',
                'Embryo implantation after in vitro fertilization',
                'Egg implantation for in vitro fertilization',
            ],
            answer: 2,
            solution: '',
        },
        {
            question:
                'The most important component of the oral contraceptive pills is –',
            options: [
                'progesterone ',
                'growth hormone',
                'thyroxin ',
                'luteinizing hormone',
            ],
            answer: 1,
            solution: '',
        },
        {
            question: 'Action of vaginal diaphragm is –',
            options: [
                'prevent the ova to come in the uterus',
                'prevent the sperm to come in contact with ova',
                'spermicidal',
                'anti-implantational',
            ],
            answer: 2,
            solution: '',
        },
        {
            question: 'Surgical removal of testes is known as –',
            options: [
                'Testectomy ',
                'Gonadectomy',
                'Castration ',
                'None of these',
            ],
            answer: 3,
            solution:
                'Permanent method of birth control in which testes are surgically removed, is called castration.',
        },
        {
            question:
                'In vitro fertilisation is a technique that involves transfer of which one of the following into the fallopian tube ?',
            options: [
                'Zygote only',
                'Embryo only, upto 8 cell stage',
                'Either zygote or early embryo upto 8 cell stage',
                'Embryo of 32 cell stage',
            ],
            answer: 3,
            solution: '',
        },
        {
            question:
                'Removal of a segment surgically and ligation of cut ends of vas deferens is known as –',
            options: ['Tubectomy ', 'Vasectomy', 'Gonadectomy ', 'Castration'],
            answer: 2,
            solution: '',
        },
        {
            question: 'Test-tube baby means a baby born when –',
            options: [
                'It develops from a non-fertilized egg',
                'It developed in a test-tube',
                'It is developed through tissue culture method',
                'The ovum is fertilised externally and thereafter implanted in the uterus',
            ],
            answer: 4,
            solution: '',
        },
        {
            question: 'Test-tube babies are produced by –',
            options: [
                'Fertilising the egg removed from the body of the female with the husband’s sperm outside in vitro culture. The zygote is transferred back to mother’s uterus',
                'External fertilisation and development in vitro culture till 32 cells stage before putting the embryo back into mother’s uterus',
                'Complete development of a baby in vitro',
                'Development upto 32 cells stage and transplanting embryo in the uterus of a surrogate mother',
            ],
            answer: 2,
            solution: '',
        },
        {
            question:
                'Which one of the following is tested by the technique of amniocentesis ?',
            options: [
                'Biochemical abnormalities in the foetus',
                'Errors of metabolism in the foetus',
                'Chromosomal abnormalities in the foetus',
                'All of the above',
            ],
            answer: 3,
            solution: '',
        },
        {
            question: 'MTP is practised mainly to –',
            options: [
                'get rid of unwanted female child legally .',
                'get rid of unwanted pregnancies due to failure of contraception of rapes.',
                'both A and B',
                'decrease population size.',
            ],
            answer: 2,
            solution: '',
        },
        {
            question:
                'Foetal sex can be determined by examining cells from the amniotic fluid by looking for–',
            options: ['Barr bodies ', 'Autosomes', 'Chiasmata ', 'Kinetochore'],
            answer: 1,
            solution: '',
        },
        {
            question: 'In amniocentesis, the fluid is taken from –',
            options: [
                'foetal blood',
                'mother’s blood',
                'body fluid of mother',
                'fluid surrounding foetus',
            ],
            answer: 4,
            solution: '',
        },
        {
            question:
                'Progesterone pill helps in preventing pregnancy by not allowing –',
            options: [
                'ova formation ',
                'gertilization',
                'implantation ',
                'None of these',
            ],
            answer: 1,
            solution: '',
        },
        {
            question:
                'Birth control pills check ovulation in female by inhibiting the secretion of –',
            options: [
                'follicle stimulating hormone',
                'luteinizing hormone',
                'both A and B',
                'None of these',
            ],
            answer: 3,
            solution: '',
        },
        {
            question:
                'Which of the following is not true about the birth control pill ?',
            options: [
                'The pill works by preventing ovulation.',
                'The pill works by preventing implantation.',
                'The ovarian cycle is suspended by the birth control pill.',
                'The birth control pill contains low doses of estrogen and progesterone.',
            ],
            answer: 2,
            solution:
                'The birth control pill interferes with the maturation of the follicles and the ova, inhibiting release of an egg.',
        },
        {
            question: 'Progestasert and LNG-20 are',
            options: [
                'implants',
                'copper releasing IUDs',
                'non-medicated IUDs',
                'hormone releasing IUDs',
            ],
            answer: 4,
            solution: ' ',
        },
        {
            question: 'The copper ions of IUDs',
            options: [
                'suppress the motility and fertilization capacity of sperms',
                'make the uterus unsuitable for implantation',
                'increase phagocytosis of sperms',
                'make cervix hostile to sperms',
            ],
            answer: 1,
            solution: '',
        },
        {
            question:
                'Which of the following birth control measures can be considered as the safest?',
            options: [
                'The rhythm method',
                'The use of physical barriers',
                'Temination of unwanted pregnancy',
                'Sterilization techniques',
            ],
            answer: 4,
            solution:
                'Sterilization techniques can be considered as the safest birth control measures. It provides a permanent and sure birth control. It is called vasectomy in male and tubectomy in female.',
        },
        {
            question:
                'Correct statement with reference to a test tube baby is :',
            options: [
                'the fertilized egg is placed in the womb of the mother where the gastrula period is completed.',
                'unfertilized egg is placed in the womb and allowed to grow parthenogenetically.',
                'a prematuraly born baby is reared in an incubator.',
                'fertilized egg is taken out and grown in a large test-tube.',
            ],
            answer: 1,
            solution:
                'For test-tube babies, fertilization of egg is done in vitro and the zygote at gastrula stage is implanted in the womb of the mother.',
        },
        {
            question:
                'Using which contraceptive also provides protection from contracting STDs and AIDS ?',
            options: [
                'Diaphragms ',
                'Spermicidal foams',
                'Condoms ',
                'Lactational amenorrhoea',
            ],
            answer: 3,
            solution: '',
        },
        {
            question: 'Action of contraceptive is',
            options: [
                'to prevent the ovulation only.',
                'prevention of ovulation and fertilization only.',
                'prevention of ovulation, fertilization and implantation only.',
                'prevent the rapid passing of eggs in oviduct.',
            ],
            answer: 2,
            solution: '',
        },
        {
            question: 'The diaphragm, cervical cap and vaults are',
            options: [
                'disposable contraceptive devices',
                'reusable contraceptives',
                'IUDs',
                'Implants',
            ],
            answer: 2,
            solution: '',
        },
        {
            question: 'In amniocentesis, the fluid is taken from',
            options: [
                'foetal blood',
                'mother’s blood',
                'body fluid of mother',
                'fluid surrounding foetus',
            ],
            answer: 4,
            solution:
                'In amniocentesis the fluid is taken from aminotic fluid, which is immediate surrounding of foetus.',
        },
        {
            question: 'Test-tube baby means a baby born when',
            options: [
                'it develops from a non-fertilized egg',
                'it developed in a test tube',
                'it is developed through tissue culture method',
                'the ovum is fertilised externally and thereafter implanted in the uterus',
            ],
            answer: 4,
            solution:
                'Test-tube baby means ovum fertilised outside the mother body and then implanted in uterus for growth and development.',
        },
        {
            question:
                'Birth control pills check ovulation in female by inhibiting the secretion of',
            options: [
                'follicle stimulating hormone (FSH)',
                'luteinizing hormone (LH)',
                'both A and B ',
                'None of these',
            ],
            answer: 3,
            solution: '',
        },
    ],
};
